<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<faqs>
    <faq>
        <id>1</id>
        <faq-category-id>1</faq-category-id>
        <question>Why is it called the Department of State?</question>
        <answer>
            <p>On September 15, 1789, Congress passed "An Act to provide for the safe keeping of the
                Acts, Records, and Seal of the United States, and for other purposes." This law
                changed the name of the Department of Foreign Affairs to the Department of State
                because certain domestic duties were assigned to the agency. These included:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Receipt, publication, distribution, and preservation of the laws of the United
                    States;</li>
                <li>Preparation, sealing, and recording of the commissions of Presidential
                    appointees;</li>
                <li>Preparation and authentication of copies of records and authentication of copies
                    under the Department's seal;</li>
                <li>Custody of the Great Seal of the United States;</li>
                <li>Custody of the records of the former Secretary of the Continental Congress,
                    except for those of the Treasury and War Departments. </li>
            </ul>
            <p>Other domestic duties that the Department was responsible for at various times
                included issuance of patents on inventions, publication of the census returns,
                management of the mint, control of copyrights, and regulation of immigration. Most
                domestic functions have been transferred to other agencies. Those that remain in the
                Department are: storage and use of the Great Seal, performance of protocol functions
                for the White House, drafting of certain Presidential proclamations, and replies to
                public inquiries. </p>
        </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <id>2</id>
        <faq-category-id>2</faq-category-id>
        <question>How many Secretaries of State have there been?</question>
        <answer> There have been 64 Secretaries of State since Thomas Jefferson was appointed to the
            position on September 26, 1789. (See List of Secretaries of State) </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <id>3</id>
        <faq-category-id>2</faq-category-id>
        <question>How many persons have served more than once as Secretary?</question>
        <answer>Two persons have held the position twice. Daniel Webster served from March 5, 1841
            to May 8, 1843, and from July 22, 1850 to October 24, 1852. James G. Blaine served from
            March 5 to December 19, 1881, and from March 5, 1889 to June 4, 1892.</answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <id>4</id>
        <faq-category-id>3</faq-category-id>
        <question>What was the shortest term of office of any Secretary of State?</question>
        <answer> Elihu B. Washburne served from March 5-16, 1869. Washburne then served as the U.S.
            Minister to France until 1877. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <id>5</id>
        <faq-category-id>3</faq-category-id>
        <question>What was the longest term of any Secretary of State?</question>
        <answer> Cordell Hull served from March 4, 1933 to November 30, 1944. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>3</faq-category-id>
        <question>Has any member of the Foreign Service served as Secretary of state?</question>
        <answer> The only member of the Foreign Service to have served as Secretary of State was
            Lawrence S. Eagleburger, who served from December 8, 1992 until January 19, 1993.
            Eagleburger had served as Acting Secretary of State from August 23, 1992. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>8</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who is the first woman Secretary of State?</question>
        <answer> Madeleine K. Albright is the first woman to have served as Secretary of State.
        </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>2</faq-category-id>
        <question>Were there equivalents to the Secretary of State prior to the Constitution?</question>
        <answer> There were two Secretaries of Foreign Affairs under the Continental Congress.
            Robert R. Livingston served from October 20, 1781 until June 4, 1783. John Jay served
            from May 7, 1784 until March 4, 1789. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>2</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the first Secretary of State to travel outside the United States while in
            office?</question>
        <answer> William H. Seward took a working vacation in the Caribbean between January 1 and
            January 28, 1866. He met with Danish colonial officials in the Virgin Islands, with the
            Presidents of the Dominican Republic and Haiti, and with Spanish colonial officials in
            Cuba. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>2</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the first Secretary of State to travel outside the United States on
            official business?</question>
        <answer> The first official travel by a Secretary of State outside the United States was by
            Elihu Root in 1906. Root left the United States on July 4 and attended the Third
            International Conference of American States in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, after which he
            visited Uruguay, Argentina, Chile, Peru, Panama, and Colombia. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>2</faq-category-id>
        <question>Was foreign travel always considered as part of a Secretary of State's duties?</question>
        <answer> Foreign travel was not always considered compatible with the office of Secretary of
            State. John W. Foster resigned in 1893 in order to head the U.S. delegation to an
            international arbitration tribunal in Paris that was seeking means to protect North
            Pacific fur seals. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>3</faq-category-id>
        <question>Why does the State Department have possession of the Great Seal?</question>
        <answer> The Department of State acquired possession of the Great Seal through an Act of
            Congress on September 15, 1789, entitled, "An Act to provide for the safe keeping of the
            Acts, Records, and Seal of the United States, and for other purposes." In the
            fulfillment of its duties, the Department of State uses the Great Seal in the
            preparation, sealing, and recording of the commissions of Presidential appointees, on
            instruments of ratification of treaties and in the preparation and authentication of
            copies of records and authentication of copies under the Department's Seal. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>3</faq-category-id>
        <question>Has the Seal always looked the same?</question>
        <answer> The Great Seal has had several different incarnations throughout U.S. history. A
            committee was formed to design the seal after a resolution was passed by the Continental
            Congress on July 4, 1776. The committee, composed of Benjamin Franklin, John Adams, and
            Thomas Jefferson, proposed the first design of the seal. Congress turned that design
            over to a second committee which proposed another design. Yet a third committee was
            appointed, and Congress adopted a final design on June 20, 1782. The first die was cut
            in 1782, and when if became worn, a new die was engraved in 1841. The 1841 seal showed
            only six arrows in the eagle's claw, used five rather than six pointed stars, and added
            fruit to the olive branch. Another die was engraved in 1877 that enlarged the stars and
            lettering of the motto; this cast is considered the poorest Great Seal die. A new die
            was engraved in 1885 using the original 1782 description as a guideline. The 185 version
            was more formal and larger than previous additions. The eagle once again held 13 arrows,
            but now he also held an olive branch with 13 leaves and 13 olives. The clouds above the
            eagle also appeared in a circle for the first time. By 1904 the 1885 seal was worn out,
            and a new seal was engraved resembling almost exactly the die of 1885. This die was used
            for 26 years and then used to create a master die in 1986. From that time the Great Seal
            has remained the same. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>3</faq-category-id>
        <question>What does the seal symbolize?</question>
        <answer> Originally the seal was meant to symbolize the beliefs and values of the founding
            fathers and the new nation. The red and white stripes of the shield represent the states
            united under and supporting the blue, representing the Chief and Congress. White
            symbolizes purity and innocence, red signifies hardiness and valor, and blue represents
            vigilance, perseverance, and justice. The shield is supported solely by the American
            eagle to denote that Americans should rely on their own virtue. The number 13, symbolic
            of the 13 original colonies, is displayed in the bundle of arrows, the stripes of the
            shield, and the stars in the constellation. The olive branch and the arrows display the
            power of peace and war. A new nation taking its place among established, sovereign
            states is represented by the constellation of stars. The motto E Pluribus Unum expresses
            the union of the 13 states. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>3</faq-category-id>
        <question>Where can I get further information about the Great Seal?</question>
        <answer> For the online text of a booklet entitled "The Great Seal of the United States", go
            to http://www.state.gov/documents/organization/27807.pdf. For a printed copy send a
            surface mailing address to history@state.gov. More detailed information appears in
            Richard S. Patterson and Richardson Dougall, The Eagle and the Shield: A History of the
            Great Seal of the United States (Washington, Department of State, 1976), 637 pages,
            illustrated. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>4</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the first U.S. Diplomat?</question>
        <answer> Benjamin Franklin was the first U.S. diplomat. He was appointed on September 26,
            1776 as part of a commission charged with gaining French support for American
            independence. He was appointed Minister to France on September 14, 1778 and presented
            his credentials on March 23, 1779, becoming the first American diplomat to be received
            by a foreign government. Franklin was one of three Commissioners who negotiated the
            peace treaty with Great Britain, and continued to serve in France until May 17, 1785. He
            was also appointed Minister to Sweden in 1782 in order to negotiate a commercial treaty
            with that country. He signed the treaty in Paris on April 3, 1783 and did not go to
            Stockholm. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>4</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the first U.S. Consul?</question>
        <answer> William Palfrey of Massachusetts was the first U.S. consul. Prior to his
            appointment as Consul to France on November 4, 1780, he had been a lieutenant colonel
            and Paymaster-General of the Continental Army. He was lost at sea on his way to his
            post. His name is the first on the memorial plaque in the lobby of the Department of
            State that honors U.S. diplomats who lost their lives under heroic or tragic
            circumstances. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>4</faq-category-id>
        <question>When was the first U.S. treaty signed?</question>
        <answer> The first U.S. treaty to be signed was a Treaty of Amity and Commerce with France
            that was signed in Paris on February 6, 1778. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>4</faq-category-id>
        <question>What was the first U.S. treaty with a non-European nation?</question>
        <answer> The first U.S. treaty with a non-European nation was a Treaty of Friendship and
            Amity that was signed with Morocco on June 23, 1786. Thomas Barclay, the U.S. Consul
            General in Paris, negotiated it. It was valid for fifty years and was renewed in 1837.
        </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>4</faq-category-id>
        <question>What was the first U.S. treaty to be ratified under the Constitution?</question>
        <answer> A consular convention with France was signed at Versailles on November 14, 1788.
            President George Washington submitted to the Senate on June 11, 1789, the Senate
            approved it on July 29, and it entered into effect on January 6, 1790. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>4</faq-category-id>
        <question>When and where was the first U.S. consular post established?</question>
        <answer> The first U.S. consular post was established in Bordeaux, France in March 1778. It
            was closed in 1996. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>4</faq-category-id>
        <question>What is the oldest diplomatic property owned by the United States?</question>
        <answer> The oldest diplomatic property owned by the United States is the U.S. Legation
            building in Tangier. The Sultan of Morocco made a gift of the building in 1821. It
            served as the U.S. Consulate and Legation until 1956. It is currently preserved as a
            museum and study center. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>5</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who were the first U.S. Ambassadors?</question>
        <answer> The rank of Ambassador was first used by the United States in 1893. Thomas F.
            Bayard was appointed Ambassador to Great Britain on March 30. James B. Eustis was
            appointed Ambassador to France on April l8. Prior to this date, the highest-ranking U.S.
            diplomats were Ministers. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>4</faq-category-id>
        <question>Which were the last U.S. diplomatic missions to become Embassies?</question>
        <answer> The last U.S. Legations (a legation is the office of a Minister) were in Bulgaria
            and Hungary. They were raised to Embassy status on November 28, 1966. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>4</faq-category-id>
        <question>Which U.S. chief of mission served for the longest time?</question>
        <answer> George P. Marsh served as Minister to Italy from March 20, 1861 until his death on
            July 23, 1882. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>4</faq-category-id>
        <question>Which U.S. chief of mission served for the shortest time?</question>
        <answer> Francis E. Meloy, Jr. was assassinated in Beirut, Lebanon, on June 16, 1976 while
            on his way to present his credentials to that country's president. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>4</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the youngest chief of a U.S. diplomatic mission?</question>
        <answer> Edward Rumsey Wing was 24 years old when he was appointed Minister to Ecuador in
            1869. Wing drank himself to death at his post in 1874. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>4</faq-category-id>
        <question>How many Ambassadors are accredited to more than one country?</question>
        <answer> As of September 30, 1997, 11 U.S. Ambassadors are accredited to more than one
            country. <ul>
                <li>The Ambassador to Barbados is also accredited to Antigua and Barbuda;Dominica;
                    Grenada; St. Kitts and Nevis; St. Lucia; and St. Vincent and the Grenadines.</li>
                <li>The Ambassador to Cameroon is also accredited to Equatorial Guinea.</li>
                <li>The Ambassador to Fiji is also accredited to Nauru, Tonga, and Tuvalu.</li>
                <li>The Ambassador to Gabon is also accredited to Sao Tome and Principe.</li>
                <li>The Ambassador to the Marshall Islands is also accredited to Kiribati.</li>
                <li>The Ambassador to Mauritius is also accredited to the Comoros and the Seychelles.</li>
                <li>The Ambassador to New Zealand is also accredited to Western Samoa.</li>
                <li>The Ambassador to Papua New Guinea is also accredited to the Solomon Islands and
                    Vanuatu.</li>
                <li>The Ambassador to the Philippines is also accredited to Palau.</li>
                <li>The Ambassador to Sri Lanka is also accredited to the Maldives.</li>
                <li>The Ambassador to Switzerland is also accredited to Liechtenstein.</li>
            </ul>
        </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>4</faq-category-id>
        <question>Were earlier Chiefs of Mission accredited to more than one country?</question>
        <answer> The first U.S. representative to the Central American States was appointed in 1825.
            Representatives were separately commissioned to Guatemala and Honduras; San Salvador (El
            Salvador); Nicaragua and Costa Rica in 1858. From 1873 to 1891, U.S. Ministers were
            commissioned to "The Central American States" but accredited to each of them. In 1891,
            one Minister was commissioned to Guatemala and Honduras and another to San Salvador,
            Costa Rica, and Nicaragua. In 1907, there were U.S. Ministers to: Guatemala; Honduras
            and San Salvador; and Costa Rica and Nicaragua. Separate Ministers to each country were
            first commissioned in 1908. <ul>
                <li>From 1882 to 1902, Ministers to Greece were also accredited to Romania
                    and Serbia. They also became Diplomatic Agents to Bulgaria in 1903. In 1905,
                    the Legation in Athens ceased to be responsible for Romania, Serbia, and Bulgaria.
                    Ministers to Athens were, however, accredited to Montenegro until that country
                    was incorporated into Yugoslavia in December 1918.</li>
                <li>From 1905 until 1919, Ministers to Romania were also accredited to Serbia and
                    Bulgaria.</li>
                <li>From 1866 to 1871, Ministers to Argentina were also accredited to Uruguay.</li>
                <li>From 1882 to 1914, Ministers to Uruguay were also accredited to Paraguay.</li>
                <li>From 1885 to 1905, Ministers to Haiti were also accredited to the Dominican
                    Republic.</li>
                <li>From 1922 to 1940, Ambassadors to Belgium were also Ministers to Luxembourg.</li>
                <li>From 1922 to 1937, Ministers to Latvia were accredited to all three
                    Baltic States. A separate Legation was established for Lithuania in 1938.
                    The Minister to Latvia was also accredited to Estonia until both countries
                    were forcibly incorporated into the Soviet Union in 1940.</li>
                <li>From 1935 to 1942, Ministers to Persia/Iran were also accredited to Afghanistan.</li>
                <li>The first U.S. Ambassador to Vietnam (1950-1954) was also accredited to Laos and
                    Cambodia.</li>
                <li>The first U.S. Ambassador to the Ivory Coast (Cote d'Ivoire) in 1960 was also
                    accredited to Dahomey (Benin), Niger, and Upper Volta (Burkina Faso).</li>
                <li>The first two U.S. Ambassadors to Botswana (1971-1976) were also accredited to
                    Lesotho and Swaziland.</li>
                <li>The record for multiple accreditations belongs to Anthony J. Drexel Biddle, Jr.,
                    who was accredited to the governments-in-exile in London of Belgium,
                    Czechoslovakia, Greece, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, Norway,Poland, and
                    Yugoslavia during World War II.</li>
            </ul>
        </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>4</faq-category-id>
        <question>How many U.S. Ambassadors have been killed by terrorists?</question>
        <answer> Five U.S. Ambassadors have been killed by terrorists: <ol>
                <li>John Gordon Mein, in Guatemala, on August 28, 1968</li>
                <li>Cleo A. Noel, Jr., in Sudan, on March 1, l973</li>
                <li>Rodger P. Davies, in Cyprus, on August 19, 1974</li>
                <li>Francis E. Meloy, Jr., in Lebanon, on June 16, 1976</li>
                <li>Adolph Dubs, Afghanistan, on February 14, 1979</li>
            </ol>
        </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>4</faq-category-id>
        <question>Have any U.S. Ambassadors died in accidents?</question>
        <answer>
            <ol>
                <li>Laurence A. Steinhardt, who was Ambassador to Canada, was killed in a plane crash
                    near Ramseyville, Ontario on March 28, 1950.</li>
                <li>Arnold L. Raphel, who was Ambassador to Pakistan, was killed in a plane crash
                    near Bahawalpur on August 17, 1988</li>
            </ol>
        </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>4</faq-category-id>
        <question>Are there some emissaries who had difficult introductions to countries in which
            they would later serve?</question>
        <answer>
            <ul>
                <li>Ambassador Douglas "Pete" Peterson, who was appointed to Vietnam in 1997,had
                    been a prisoner of war there from 1966 to 1973.</li>
                <li>Richard O'Brien, a mariner from Philadelphia, was captured by Barbary Pirates in
                    1785 and spent more then ten years as a captive in Algiers. During this time he
                    was a spokesman for his fellow American captives and corresponded with the
                    Department of State. When diplomatic relations were established with Algiers in
                    1796, O'Brien went back as Consul General,helped establish relations with Tunis
                    and Tripoli, and served until 1803.</li>
                <li>James Leander Cathcart, one of O'Brien's fellow captives, would be the first U.S.
                    Consul in Tripoli.</li>
            </ul>
        </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>6</faq-category-id>
        <question>Have there been multi-generational foreign affairs families inU.S. history?</question>
        <answer>
            <ul>
                <li>John Adams was the first U.S. Minister to the United Kingdom. He was appointed
                    February 24, 1785, presented his credentials to King George III on June 1, 1785,
                    and served until February 20, 1788. His son John Quincy Adams was the first U.S.
                    Minister to the United Kingdom after the War of 1812. He was appointed February
                    28, 1815, and served until May 14, 1817. Grandson Charles Francis Adams served
                    from 1861 to 1868. Much of his work involved keeping Britain neutral during the
                    Civil War and negotiating post war agreements with Britain to settle U.S. claims
                    for damages against that country.</li>
                <li>A family of English Quaker merchants named Fox were U.S. Consuls at Falmouth,
                    England. Robert Were Fox served from 1794 to 1812, and again from1815 to his
                    death in 1818. Robert Were Fox , Jr. served from 1819 to 1854(their middle name
                    is sometimes spelled "Weare" or "Ware"). Somehow the Consulate passed out of the
                    family between 1854 and 1863. Two more generations of Foxes then served. Alfred
                    Fox was appointed in 1863, and Howard Fox served from 1874 until the post was
                    closed in December 1905.</li>
                <li>Three generations of the Sprague family served as Consuls in Gibraltar. Horatio
                    Sprague was appointed in 1832 and served until his death in 1848.His son Horatio
                    J. Sprague served from 1848 until his death in 1901.Grandson Richard L. Sprague
                    served from 1901 until his death in 1934. </li>
            </ul>
        </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>6</faq-category-id>
        <question>Have any children of Secretaries of State served in the State Department at the
            same time as their fathers?</question>
        <answer> Three sons of Secretaries of State held high positions in the Department while
            their fathers served. <ul>
                <li>Daniel Webster's eldest son, Daniel Fletcher Webster, served as Chief Clerk of
                    the Department of State from March 6, 1841 to April 23, 1843. The Chief Clerk was
                    at this time the second-ranking officer in the Department.</li>
                <li>Frederick W. Seward, son of William H. Seward, served as Assistant Secretary of
                    State (then the second-ranking officer) from March 6, 1861 to March 4, 1869.</li>
                <li>Walker Blaine, son of James G. Blaine, served as Third Assistant Secretary of
                    State from July 1, 1881 to June 30, 1882. </li>
            </ul>
        </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>6</faq-category-id>
        <question>Have any married couples served simultaneously as Ambassadors?</question>
        <answer> Four married couples have served simultaneously as Ambassadors. <ul>
                <li>Ellsworth Bunker (Ambassador at Large, 1966-67; Ambassador to Vietnam,1967-1973
                    ) and Carol Laise (Nepal 1966-1973)</li>
                <li>Carleton S. Coon, Jr., (Nepal 1981-84) and Jane Abell Coon (Bangladesh1981-84)</li>
                <li>William R. Brownfield (Chile 2002-2004; Venezuela 2004- ) and Kristie Kenney
                    (Ecuador 2002- )</li>
                <li>Charles Ries (Greece 2004- ) and Marcie Ries (Albania 2004- )</li>
            </ul>
        </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>6</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who are some distinguished writers who have held diplomatic,consular, or senior
            State Department posts?</question>
        <answer>
            <ul>
                <li>Washington Irving, Minister to Spain, 1842-46.</li>
                <li>Nathaniel Hawthorne, Consul at Liverpool, 1853-57.</li>
                <li>Bret Harte, Consul at Crefeld, 1878-1880, and at Glasgow, 1880-1885.</li>
                <li>James Russell Lowell, Minister to Spain, 1877-80; to Great Britain,1880-85.</li>
                <li>James Fenimore Cooper, Consul at Lyon, 1826.</li>
                <li>Lewis (Lew) Wallace, Minister to Turkey, 1881-85.</li>
                <li>John Howard Payne, Consul at Tunis, 1842-45 and 1851-52.</li>
                <li>John Lathrop Motley, Minister to Austria, 1861-67; to Great Britain1869-70.</li>
                <li>William Dean Howells, Consul at Venice, 1861-65.</li>
                <li>Archibald MacLeish, Assistant Secretary of State for Public
                Affairs,1944-45.</li>
            </ul>
        </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>7</faq-category-id>
        <question>What Act Created the State Department</question>
        <answer> Article II, section 2 of the Constitution authorized the President to appoint, by
            and with the advice and consent of the Senate, "Ambassadors, other public Ministers, and
            Consuls." From 1789 until 1924, the Diplomatic Service, which staffed U.S. Legations and
            Embassies, and the Consular Service, which was primarily responsible for promoting
            American commerce and assisting distressed American sailors, developed separately.
        </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>7</faq-category-id>
        <question>When was the Consular Service established?</question>
        <answer> The first Act of Congress providing for U.S. consuls abroad was passed on April 14,
            1792. Except for the consuls appointed to the Barbary States of North Africa (who
            enjoyed quasi-diplomatic status when Muslim countries did not maintain permanent
            missions abroad), U.S. consuls received no salary and were expected to earn their
            livings from private trade or from fees charged for official services. It was not
            uncommon for consuls to have been merchants with business connections in the cities to
            which they had been appointed. They did not have to be U.S. citizens. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>7</faq-category-id>
        <question>When did U.S. consuls first receive a salary?</question>
        <answer> An Act of Congress of August 18, 1856 established two schedules of consular posts.
            Consuls appointed to Schedule B posts were paid between $1,000 and $7,500 per year. They
            could still collect fees, but could no longer engage in trade. Schedule C appointees
            received between $500 and $1,000 per year and could engage in trade. Non-citizens might
            be appointed to consular posts, but could not be paid. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>7</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who were the first professional consular appointees?</question>
        <answer> The Act of August 18, 1856 provided for the appointment of up to 25 "consular
            pupils", who would take an examination before their appointment and be assigned to
            consulates at the discretion of the President. This provision was repealed during the
            next session of Congress. On June 20, 1864, Congress authorized 13 consular clerks.
            Between 1864 and 1896, 64 consular clerks were appointed. Only 8 were promoted to
            consul; most preferred a small ($1,000) salary and security to a larger one of uncertain
            duration. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>7</faq-category-id>
        <question>What was the forerunner of the Foreign Service Examination?</question>
        <answer> President Grover Cleveland issued an Executive Order on September 20, 1895 that
            required appointees to consular positions with salaries between $1,000 and $2,500 to be
            either a qualified officer of the Department, or to pass a written examination on
            consular regulations and an oral examination that included demonstrating proficiency in
            a foreign language. Executive orders issued by President Theodore Roosevelt on November
            10, 1905 and June 27, 1906 instituted examinations for the lower grades of the Consular
            Service and for secretaries in the Diplomatic Service. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>7</faq-category-id>
        <question>When was the present-day Foreign Service established?</question>
        <answer> The Rogers Act (named for Rep. John Jacob Rogers) of May 24, 1924 amalgamated the
            Diplomatic and Consular Services into a unified Foreign Service. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>8</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who were the first women in the Foreign Service?</question>
        <answer> Lucile Atcherson passed the Diplomatic Service examination in 1922 with the
            third-highest score, and was appointed a secretary in the Diplomatic Service on December
            5, 1922. She was assigned as Third Secretary of the Legation in Berne, Switzerland, on
            April 11, 1925. She resigned September 19, 1927 in order to get married. Pattie H. Field
            was the first woman to enter the Foreign Service after passage of the Rogers Act. She
            was sworn in on April 20, 1925, served as a Vice Consul at Amsterdam, and resigned on
            June 27, 1929 to accept a job with the National Broadcasting Company. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>8</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the first woman to be chief of a U.S. diplomatic mission?</question>
        <answer> Ruth Bryan Owen, daughter of William Jennings Bryan, was appointed Minister to
            Denmark on April 13, 1933. She presented her credentials on May 29, 1933 and served
            until June 27, 1936. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>8</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the first woman to hold the rank of Ambassador?</question>
        <answer> Eugenie Moore Anderson was appointed Ambassador to Denmark on October 20, 1949. She
            presented her credentials on December 22, 1949, and served until January 19, 1953.
        </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>8</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the first woman Foreign Service Officer to become an Ambassador?</question>
        <answer> Frances E. Willis was appointed Ambassador to Switzerland on July 20, 1953, and
            presented her credentials on October 9. She served until May 5, 1957. She later served
            as Ambassador to Norway (1957-1961) and Ambassador to Ceylon (now Sri Lanka)
            (1961-1964). Willis was the third woman Foreign Service Officer, being appointed on
            August 29, 1927. She was appointed Career Ambassador on March 20, 1962. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>8</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the first woman to become an Assistant Secretary of State?</question>
        <answer> Carol C. Laise was appointed Assistant Secretary of State for Public Affairs on
            September 20, 1973. She served until March 27, 1975. She then served as Director General
            of the Foreign Service from April 11, 1975 to December 26, 1977. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>8</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the first woman to head one of the regional bureaus?</question>
        <answer> Rozanne L. Ridgway was appointed Assistant Secretary of State for European and
            Canadian Affairs on July 18, 1985. She served until June 30, 1989. She had also been the
            first woman to serve as Counselor of the Department of State (March 18, 1980-February
            24, 1981). </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>8</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the first woman Under Secretary of State?</question>
        <answer> Lucy Wilson Benson was appointed Under Secretary of State for Security Assistance,
            Science, and Technology on March 23, 1977 and served until January 5, 1980. At the time
            of her appointment, she was the highest-ranking woman in the Department. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>9</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the first African-American diplomat?</question>
        <answer> Ebenezer Don Carlos Basset was the first African-American diplomat. He was Minister
            Resident and Consul General in Haiti from 1869 to 1877. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>9</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the first African-American consul?</question>
        <answer> On October 29, 1845, Thomas O. Larkin, U.S. Consul in Monterey, California (then
            part of Mexico) appointed William A. Leidesdorff as Vice Consul at Yerba Buena (now San
            Francisco). Leidesdorff was born in the Danish West Indies (now the U.S. Virgin Islands)
            to a Danish planter and an Afro-Caribbean woman in 1810. He was naturalized as a U.S.
            citizen in 1834 while living in New Orleans. While living in California, he became a
            Mexican citizen in 1844 in order to increase his landholdings. His service as Vice
            Consul lasted until U.S. forces occupied northern California in July 1846. Leidesdorff
            died in San Francisco on May 18, 1848. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>9</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the first African-American to hold the rank of Ambassador?</question>
        <answer> Edward R. Dudley was appointed Minister to Liberia in 1948 and promoted to
            Ambassador to Liberia in 1949. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>9</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the first African-American to join the Foreign Service?</question>
        <answer> Clifton R. Wharton joined the Foreign Service in 1925. He became the first
            African-American Foreign Service Officer to become chief of a diplomatic mission when he
            was appointed Minister to Romania on February 5, 1958. This appointment made him the
            first of his race to be chief of a diplomatic mission to a European country. He served
            in Romania until October 21, 1960. He then served as Ambassador to Norway from April 18,
            1961 to September 4, 1964. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>9</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the First African-American to Become Secretary of State?</question>
        <answer> Colin Powell appointed Secretary of State by President George W. Bush in January
            2001, was the first African-American Secretary of State. As Secretary of State, he was
            the highest ranking official of the Department. Prior to Secretary Powell, Clifton R.
            Wharton, Jr. had been the highest ranking African-American in the Department. He served
            as Deputy Secretary of State (the number two position in the Department) from January
            27 to November 8, 1973, and was the son of pioneering Foreign Service Officer Clifton R.
            Wharton. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>8</faq-category-id>
        <faq-category-id>9</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the first African-American woman to become Secretary of State?</question>
        <answer> Condoleezza Rice became the 66th Secretary of State under President George W. Bush
            on January 26, 2005, and is the first African-American woman to serve as Secretary of
            State. As Secretary of State, she is the highest ranking official of the Department.
        </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>8</faq-category-id>
        <faq-category-id>9</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the first African-American woman to become an Ambassador?</question>
        <answer> Patricia Roberts Harris was appointed Ambassador to Luxembourg on June 4, 1965, and
            presented her credentials on September 7. She served until September 22, 1967. </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <faq-category-id>9</faq-category-id>
        <question>Who was the first African-American to become chief of a State Department bureau?</question>
        <answer> Barbara M. Watson became Administrator of the Bureau of Security and Consular
            Affairs on July 31, 1968, and served until December 31, 1974. She was re-appointed on
            April 7, 1977. On August 17 of that year, she became Assistant Secretary of State for
            Consular Affairs, and served until September 11, 1980. </answer>
    </faq>
</faqs>